# Sandeep Chauhan

+91-6005030657

<u>Stackoverflow Github LinkedIn</u> <u>sandeepsajan0@gmail.com</u> <u>Moradabad, India</u>

**Summary** I'm a Software Developer with 2-3 years of volunteer experience in application development. I have major experience with Python and Django. I love to work remotely with global developers. I always welcome the new technology-based projects. I have good problem-solving skills. I am a quick learner and passionate about scaling the applications.

## **Experience**

Intern at Spoonshot (Full-stack developer)

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Scaling and performance improvements of web crawlers implemented using Python/Django.
- Deployed a proxymanager for scraping framework on Django server with Redis.
- Dockerize the scraping framework and scale it with mongodb, celery workers and aws.
- Implement monitoring system with Grafana and influxdb.

## **Google Summer of Code Student**

Apr 2018 - Aug 2018

- Python based implementation of <u>Hydra Client</u>.
- Implemented Hydra Client with the datastore Redis which also works as a cache for Hydrus.
- Developed a web app using flask for hydra-client demo.

## **Open Source Contribution**

#### **Hydra Ecosystem**

- hydra-python-agent One of the main contributor who have built this project.
  Implemented Redis as a graph database using redisgraph and Cypher. Also created a Docker env., write tests, use designing patterns and etc.
- hydrus Add UUID in database and also add auto documentation using sphinx and fix some easy issues.
- hydra-astrodemo Created a demo for hydra-client using flask which also using the hydra-parser and hydrus server.
- http-apis.github.io Write documention for all the work done by me and also for some other projects related to my work.

#### **Kivy**

Fixed issue to integrate plyer with android as expected.

## **Projects**

# Go Web App

A Web app implemented with Golang using Redis as database having features routing, authentication, middleware, comments, error handling. It is a good reference for beginners because of its modules and good structure.

# • Reactjs Projects

- Calculator
- o router-sample
- friends\_passion(Beginner-friendly project to iterate over json data)
- ReactSwapi Api( React app to consume api and show data of swapi.co)

#### Friends

An anonymous web chat app implemented with Python, Django, Reactjs with database sqlite3 have some great functionalities like authentication, public and private groups(without showing users name), API's, messaging/posting, API's data presenting using Reactjs.

# Social Networking

A blogpost web app which implemented using Python, Django and PostgreSQL as a database having features like authentication, manage profiling, blogs posting (with date and name). It is live or deployed on heroku.

## Some small projects to become familiar with these technologies

- o Implement Redis with flask.
- Snake game based on pygame.
- Some simple apps based on kivy plyer.
- A simple kit-kat game using python.

#### **Education**

• Bachelor of Technology(2016-Present)

Shri Mata Vaishno Devi University, katra, India

#### **Miscellaneous**

- Student Coordinator at The CodeClub, SMVDU.
- Conduct and organize the various workshops, and programs like SFD.

#### **Skills**

**Backend Development:** Python(Django, Flask), Golang **Frontend Development:** React.js, HTML and CSS, JS **Databases:** PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Mongodb, sqlite

**Operating System:** Linux(ubuntu)

Other tools: Git, Bash, Docker, Celery, RabbitMQ, Grafana, influxdb, AWS